I'm going to talk about a very fundamental change that is going on
سأتحدث عن تغييرات أساسية تجري حالياً
in the very fabric of the modern economy.
في جسم نسيج الإقتصاد الحديث.
And to talk about that, I'm going to go back to the beginning,
ولأتحدث عن ذلك، سأرجع إلى البداية،
because in the beginning were commodities.
لأن في البداية كانت هناك سلع.
Commodities are things that you grow in the ground, raise on the ground or pull out of the ground:
السلع هي أشياء تقوم بزرعها على الأرض، تربيها على الأرض أو تستخرجها من الأرض:
basically, animal, mineral, vegetable.
مثل الحيوانات، المعادن، الخضروات.
And then you extract them out of the ground,
ثم تستخلصها من الأرض،
and sell them on the open marketplace.
وتبيعها في السوق المفتوح.
Commodities were the basis of the agrarian economy
كانت السلع هي أساس الإقتصاد الزراعي
that lasted for millennia.
الذي أنتهى قبل آلاف السنين.
But then along came the industrial revolution,
ثم جاءت الثورة الصناعية،
and then goods became the predominant economic offering,
وعندئذ أصبحت البضائع الطرح السائد إقتصادياً،
where we used commodities as a raw material
حيث أستخدمنا السلع مثل المواد الخام
to be able to make or manufacture goods.
لنقدر على تصنيع البضائع.
So, we moved from an agrarian economy to an industrial economy.
لذا، فقد إنتقلنا من إقتصاد زراعي إلى إقتصاد صناعي.
Well, what then happened over the last 50 or 60 years,
حسناً، ماذا حدث بعد ذلك خلال ال 50 إلى 60 سنة الماضية،
is that goods have become commoditized.
هو أن البضائع أصبحت أكثر سلعية.
Commoditized: where they're treated like a commodity,
تسلعت: حيث يتم التعامل معها كسلعة،
where people don't care who makes them.
حيث لا يأبه الناس بمن صنعهم.
They just care about three things and three things only:
إنهم يهتمون فقط بثلاثة أشياء وفقط ثلاثة أشياء:
price, price and price.
السعر، السعر، السعر.
Now, there's an antidote to commoditization,
الآن ، هناك ترياق للسلع الإستهلاكية ،
and that is customization.
وذلك هو التخصيص.
My first book was called "Mass Customization" --
أول كتبي كان يسمى " التصنيع حسب الطلب" --
it came up a couple of times yesterday --
لقد ذُكر أكثر من مرة بالأمس--
and how I discovered this progression of economic value
وكيف قمت بإكتشاف أن هذا التقدم لقيمة الإقتصاد
was realizing that customizing a good
كان يدرك بأن تخصيص السلع
automatically turned it into a service,
يتحول آلياً إلى خدمات،
because it was done just for a particular person,
لأنها كانت تتم لشخص محدد،
because it wasn't inventoried,
لأنها لم تكن قد جُردت،
it was delivered on demand to that individual person.
لقد تم إرسالها حسب الطلب لذلك الشخص.
So, we moved from an industrial economy to a service-based economy.
لذا، فقد أنتقلنا من الإقتصاد الصناعي لذلك الشخص الفرد.
But over the past 10 or 20 years, what's happened is that
لكن خلال ال 10 أو العشرين سنة الماضية، الذي حدث هو
services are being commoditized as well.
أن الخدمات تم تسليعها أيضاً.
Long-distance telephone service sold on price, price, price;
الإتصالات الخارجية تم بيعها حسب السعر، السعر، السعر.
fast-food restaurants with all their value pricing;
مطاعم الوجبات السريعة مع كل قيمتها السعرية.
and even the Internet is commoditizing not just goods,
وحتى الإنترنت تم تسليعها ليس مجرد بضائع،
but services as well.
بل خدمات أيضاً.
What that means is that it's time
ما يعنيه ذلك هو أن الوقت
to move to a new level of economic value.
قد حان للإنتقال إلى مستوى جديد من قيمة الإقتصاد.
Time to go beyond the goods and the services,
الوقت قد حان للذهاب لأبعد من البضائع والخدمات،
and use, in that same heuristic, what happens when you customize a service?
والإستخدام، بنفس التوجه، ماذا يحدث عند تخصيص الخدمات؟
What happens when you design a service that is so appropriate for a particular person --
ماذا يحدث عندما تصمم خدمة مناسبة جداً لشخص محدد --
that's exactly what they need at this moment in time?
وذلك بالضبط الذي يحتاجوه في هذه اللحظة من الوقت؟
Then you can't help but make them go "wow";
عندها لا يمكنك المساعدة في جعلهم يقولون "واااو".
you can't help but turn it into a memorable event --
لا يمكنك المساعدة بل تحويلها إلى حدث تذكاري--
you can't help but turn it into an experience.
لا يمكنك المساعدة بل تحويلها إلى تجربة.
So we're shifting to an experience economy,
إذاً فنحن نتحول إلى إقتصاد التجربة،
where experiences are becoming the predominant economic offering.
حيث تصبح الخبرات هي الطرح الإقتصادي السائد.
Now most places that I talk to,
معظم الأماكن التي تحدث إليها،
when I talk about experience, I talk about Disney --
حينما أتحدث عن التجربة، أتحدث عن ديزني--
the world's premier experience-stager.
مسرح التجارب الرائد عالمياً.
I talk about theme restaurants, and experiential retail,
أتحدث عن شعارات المطاعم، التجربة العريقة في متاجر التجزئة،
and boutique hotels, and Las Vegas --
وباقات الفنادق، ولاس فيجاس --
the experience capital of the world.
عاصمة التجربة في العالم.
But here, when you think about experiences,
لكن هنا، حينما تفكر بالتجارب،
think about Thomas Dolby and his group, playing music.
فكر ب توماس دولبي ومجموعته، يلعبون الموسيقى.
Think about meaningful places.
فكروا بأماكن ذات معنى.
Think about drinking wine,
فكروا بتجرع النبيذ،
about a journey to the Clock of the Long Now.
حول الرحلة لساعة زمن من الآن.
Those are all experiences. Think about TED itself.
تلك كلها تجارب. فكروا حول تيد نفسه.
The experience capital in the world of conferences.
عاصمة الخبرات في عالم المؤتمرات.
All of these are experiences.
كل هذه خبرات.
Now, over the last several years I spent a lot of time in Europe,
الآن، خلال الأعوام القليلة الماضية التي قضيت الكثير منها في أوروبا،
and particularly in the Netherlands,
وتحديداً في هولندا،
and whenever I talk about the experience economy there,
وكلما أتحدث عن إقتصاد التجربة هناك،
I'm always greeted at the end with one particular question,
دائماً ما يتم إلقاء سؤال واحد عقب نهاية الحديث،
almost invariably.
في كل الحالات تقريباً.
And the question isn't really so much a question
والسؤال لا يشبه السؤال الحقيقي
as an accusation.
شئ مثل الإتهام.
And the Dutch, when they usually put it,
والهولنديون، عندما يضعونها عادةً،
it always starts with the same two words.
فانها دائماً تبدأ بنفس الكلمتين.
You know the words I mean?
تعرفون الكلمة التي أعنيها؟
You Americans.
أنتم الأمريكان.
They say, you Americans.
إنهم يقولون، أنتم الأمريكان.
You like your fantasy environments,
تحبون بيئاتكم الخيالية،
your fake, your Disneyland experiences.
أوهامكم، تجاربكم في ديزني لاند.
They say, we Dutch, we like real,
يقولون، نحن الهولنديون، نحب الحقيقة،
natural, authentic experiences.
الطبيعة، التجارب الأصلية.
So much has that happened that I've developed a fairly praticed response,
والكثير مما حدث جعلني قمت بتطوير إستجابة مجربة،
which is: I point out that first of all,
التي هي: لقد اشرت لهذا قبل كل شئ،
you have to understand that there is no such thing
ينبغي أن تفهم أنه لا يوجد مثل هذا الشئ
as an inauthentic experience.
كتجربة زائفة.
Why? Because the experience happens inside of us.
لماذا؟ لأن التجربة تحدث داخلنا.
It's our reaction to the events that are staged in front of us.
إنها رد فعلنا للأحداث التي مثلت أمامنا.
So, as long as we are in any sense authentic human beings,
لذا، طالما أننا بأي حال بشر أصليون،
then every experience we have is authentic.
إذاً فكل تجربة نشهدها هي أصلية.
Now, there may be more or less natural or artificial
الآن، قد يكون هناك محفزات أكثر أو أقل
stimuli for the experience,
طبيعية أو إصطناعية للتجربة،
but even that is a matter of degree, not kind.
لكن حتى ذلك مسألة مقدار، وليس نوع.
And there's no such thing as a 100 percent natural experience.
وليس هناك شئ مثل 100 بالمائة تجربة طبيعية.
Even if you go for a walk in the proverbial woods,
حتى إذا ذهبت للنزهة في الغابات،
there is a company that manufactured the car
فهناك شركة التي تصنع السيارة
that delivered you to the edge of the woods;
التي أوصلتك إلى حافة الغابة.
there's a company that manufactured the shoes that you have
هناك شركة صنعت الأحذية التي تملكها
to protect yourself from the ground of the woods.
لحماية نفسك من أرض الغابة.
There's a company that provides a cell phone service you have
وهناك شركة تقدم خدمة الهاتف المحمول الذي تملكه
in case you get lost in the woods.
في حالة ضياعك في الغابة.
Right? All of those are man-made,
صحيح؟ كل هذه من صنع الإنسان،
artificiality brought into the woods by you,
جُلبت إلى الغابة إفتراضاً بواسطتك،
and by the very nature of being there.
وبطبيعة ما يحدث هناك.
And then I always finish off
ثم أُنهي الحديث
by talking about -- the thing that amazes me the most about this question,
بالتحدث حول -- الشئ الذي يدهشني أكثر حول هذا السؤال،
particularly coming from the Dutch,
الذي يأتي تحديداً من الهولنديين،
is that the Netherlands
في هولندا
is every bit as manufactured as Disneyland.
أن كل شئ في هولندا مصنوع كما ديزني لاند.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
And the Dutch, they always go ...
والهولنديون، دائما يقولون...
and they realize, I'm right!
ويدركون، أنني على حق!
There isn't a square meter of ground in the entire country
لا يوجد ولا متر مربع في كل الدولة
that hasn't been reclaimed from the sea,
لم يتم إستصلاحه من البحر،
or otherwise moved, modified and manicured
أو غير ذلك تم نقله، وتعديله وتشذيبه
to look as if it had always been there.
ليبدو كما لو كان دائماً هكذا.
It's the only place you ever go for a walk in the woods and all the trees are lined up in rows.
إنه المكان الوحيد الذي تذهب إليه للتمشي في الغابات وكل الأشجار تصطف في صفوف.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But nonetheless, not just the Dutch,
لكن ومع ذلك، ليس فقط الهولنديون،
but everyone has this desire for the authentic.
لكن لدى كل شخص الرغبة في الأصالة.
And authenticity is therefore
والإصالة عندئذ
becoming the new consumer sensibility --
تصبح حساسية المستهلك الجديد --
the buying criteria by which consumers
معايير الشراء التي عبرها سيختار
are choosing who are they going to buy from,
المستهلك من الذي سيشتري منه،
and what they're going to buy.
وماذا سيشترون.
Becoming the basis of the economy.
تصبح أسس الإقتصاد.
In fact, you can look at how each of these economies developed,
في الحقيقة، يمكنك النظر على كيف نمت كل من هذه الإقتصاديات،
that each one has their own business imperative,
التي لكل منها تجاربه التجارية الخاصة،
matched with a consumer sensibility.
متطابقة مع حساسية المستهلك.
We're the agrarian economy, and we're supplying commodities.
في الإقتصاد الزراعي، نحن نوفر السلع.
It's about supply and availability.
إنه يدور حول التزويد والوفرة.
Getting the commodities to market.
إيصال السلع إلى السوق.
With the industrial economy, it is about controlling costs --
مع الإقتصاد الصناعي، إنه حول التحكم في التكاليف--
getting the costs down as low as possible
تقليل التكاليف بقدر الإمكان
so we can offer them to the masses.
بحيث يمكننا عرضها على الجموع.
With the service economy, it is about
مع إقتصاد الخدمات، إنه حول
improving quality.
تحسين الجودة.
That has -- the whole quality movement has risen
التي لديها -- حركة الجودة الكلية قد أرتفعت
with the service economy over the past 20 or 30 years.
مع إقتصاد الخدمات خلال ال 20 أو ال 30 سنة الماضية.
And now, with the experience economy,
والآن، مع إقتصاد التجربة،
it's about rendering authenticity.
إنها حول إستدعاء الأصالة.
Rendering authenticity -- and the keyword is "rendering."
إستدعاء الأصالة-- والكلمة المفتاحية هي " إستدعاء."
Right? Rendering, because you have to get your consumers --
صحيح؟ إستدعاء، لأنه ينبغي أن يكون مستهلكيك--
as business people --
مثل رجال الأعمال--
to percieve your offerings as authentic.
لإعتبار أن عروضك أصلية.
Because there is a basic paradox:
لأن هناك تناقض أساسي:
no one can have an inauthentic experience,
لا يمكن لشخص الحصول على تجربة زائفة،
but no business can supply one.
لكن لا يمكن لعمل تجاري تقديم تجربة زائفة.
Because all businesses are man-made objects; all business is involved with money;
لكن كل الأعمال هي أشياء من صنع البشر. كل الأعمال التي يدخل فيها المال.
all business is a matter of using machinery,
كل الأعمال تدور حول مسألة إستخدام الآلات،
and all those things make something inauthentic.
وكل هذه الأشياء تجعلها غير أصلية.
So, how do you render authenticity,
لذا، كيف يمكننا إستدعاء الأصالة،
is the question.
هو السؤال.
Are you rendering authenticity?
هل تستدعي الأصالة؟
When you think about that, let me go back to
حينما تفكر بذلك، دعوني أرجع إلى
what Lionel Trilling, in his seminal book on authenticity,
ما ردده ليونال، في كتابه المبدع حول الأصالة،
"Sincerity and Authenticity" -- came out in 1960 --
"الإخلاص والأصالة"-- صدر في عام 1960--
points to as the seminal point
يشير لها كنقطة جوهرية
at which authenticity entered the lexicon,
التي دخلت فيها الأصالة القاموس،
if you will.
إذا شئتم.
And that is, to no surprise, in Shakespeare,
وذلك هو، بدون مفاجأة، في مسرحية
and in his play, Hamlet.
شكسبير، هاملت.
And there is one part in this play, Hamlet,
وهناك جزء في مسرحيته، هاملت،
where the most fake of all the characters in Hamlet, Polonius,
حيث يقول أكثر الشخصيات الوهمية في هاملت، بولونيوس،
says something profoundly real.
شيئاً حقيقياً بعمق.
At the end of a laundry list of advice
في نهاية قائمة النصائح
he's giving to his son, Laertes,
التي يقدمها لأبنه، لارتس،
he says this:
يقول الآتي:
And this above all: to thine own self be true.
قبل كل شيء : كن صادقا مع نفسك
And it doth follow, as night the day,
وسيتبع ذلك – كما يتبع الليل النهار-
that thou canst not then be false to any man.
أنك لن تستطيع أن تكذب على أحدا من الناس.
And those three verses are the core of authenticity.
وتلك الفقرات الثلاث هي جوهر الأصالة.
There are two dimensions to authenticity:
وهناك بُعدين للأصالة:
one, being true to yourself, which is very self-directed.
الأول، أن تكون صادقاً مع نفسك، الذي هو مرتبط بشدة بالنفس.
Two, is other-directed:
الثاني، غاية في الذاتية:
being what you say you are to others.
أن تكون ما تقوله للآخرين.
And I don't know about you, but whenever I encounter two dimensions,
ولا أعرف عنكم، لكن كلما واجهت هذين البُعدين،
I immediately go, ahh, two-by-two!
أقول في الحال، آه، أثنين لأثنين!
All right? Anybody else like that, no?
صحيح؟ أي شخص آخر يحب ذلك، لا؟
Well, if you think about that, you do, in fact, get
حسناً، إذا فكرتم بها، فأنكم ستحصلون في الواقع
a two-by-two.
على أثنين لأثنين.
Where, on one dimension it's a matter of being true to yourself.
حيث، على بُعد واحد الأمر مرتبط بالصدق مع النفس.
As businesses, are the economic offerings you are providing --
للأعمال التجارية، تقوم العروض الإقتصادية بتوفير --
are they true to themselves?
هل هم صادقين مع أنفسهم؟
And the other dimension is:
وعلى البُعد الآخر:
are they what they say they are to others?
هل يجسدون هم ما يقولونه للآخرين؟
If not, you have,
إن لم يكن، ستحصل،
"is not true to itself," and "is not what it says it is,"
" ليس صادقاً مع نفسه"، و " وليس كما يقول عن نفسه،"
yielding a two-by-two matrix.
ويرضخ لمصفوفة أثنين لأثنين.
And of course, if you are both true to yourself,
وبالطبع، إذا كنت صادقاً مع نفسك،
and are what you say you are, then you're real real!
وتجسد ما تقوله عن نفسك، فأنت حقيقي حقيقي!
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
The opposite, of course, is -- fake fake.
العكس، بالطبع، هو -- مزيف مزيف.
All right, now, there is value for fake.
صحيح؟ الآن، هناك قيمة للزيف.
There will always be companies around to supply the fake,
توجد دائماً شركات تقدم الزيف،
because there will always be desire for the fake.
لأنه ستكون هناك رغبة دائمة للتزييف.
Fact is, there's a general rule: if you don't like it, it's fake;
الحقيقة هي، هناك قاعدة عامة: إن كنت لا تحبها، فهي مزيفة.
if you do like it, it's faux.
وإذا كنت تحبها، فهي خطأ.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
Now, the other two sides of the coin are:
الآن، هناك جوانب أخرى للعملة وهي:
being a real fake --
أن تكون مزيف حقاً--
is what it says it is,
وهو ما يقوله هو،
but is not true to itself,
لكنه ليس صادقاً مع نفسه،
or being a fake real:
أو تزيف الحقيقة:
is true to itself, but not what it says it is.
صادق مع نفسه، لكنه ليس ما يقول.
You can think about those two -- you know, both of these
يمكنكم التفكير بهذين الأثنين-- كما تعلمون، كلا منهم
better than being fake fake -- not quite as good as being real real.
أفضل من كونك مزيف الزيف -- ليس أفضل من كونك حقيقي حقيقي.
You can contrast them by thinking about
يمكنك عكسهم بالتفكير حول
Universal City Walk versus
يونيفرسال سيتي والك مقابل
Disney World, or Disneyland.
عالم ديزني، أو ديزني لاند.
Universal City Walk is a real fake --
يونيفرسال سيتي والك هو زيف حقيقي--
in fact, we got this very term
في الواقع، لقد عرفنا هذا المصطلح تحديداً
from Ada Louise Huxtable's book, "The Unreal America."
من كتاب أدا لويز هاكستابل، " أمريكا المزيفة."
A wonderful book, where she talks about Universal City Walk as --
كتاب رائع، حيث تتحدث عن يونيفرسال سيتي والك ك --
you know, she decries the fake, but she says, at least that's a real fake,
كما تعلمون، فهي تشجب الزيف، لكنها تقول، على الأقل هذا زيف حقيقي،
right, because you can see behind the facade, right?
صحيح، لأنه يمكنك رؤية خلف الستار، صحيح؟
It is what it says it is: It's Universal Studio;
إنها ليست كما تقول عن نفسها: إنها أستديو عالمي.
it's in the city of Los Angeles; you're going to walk a lot.
إنه في مدينة لوس أنجلوس. وينبغي عليك السير كثيراً.
Right? You don't tend to walk a lot in Los Angeles,
صحيح؟ فأنت لا تميل للسير كثيراً في لوس أنجلوس،
well, here's a place where you are going to walk a lot,
حسناً، ها هو المكان حيث ستسير كثيراً،
outside in this city.
من خارج هذه المدينة.
But is it really true to itself?
لكن هل حقاً صادق مع نفسه؟
Right? Is it really in the city?
صحيح؟ هل هي حقاً في المدينة؟
Is it --
هل هي --
you can see behind all of it,
يمكنك رؤية خلف كل ذلك،
and see what is going on in the facades of it.
ورؤية ما يجري في واجهتها.
So she calls it a real fake.
لذا فهي تسميه زيف حقيقي.
Disney World, on the other hand, is a fake real,
عالم ديزني، على الجانب الآخر، هل الزيف الحقيقي،
or a fake reality.
أو تحقيق الزيف.
Right? It's not what it says it is. It's not really the magic kingdom.
صحيح؟ إنها ليست ما تقوله عن نفسها. إنه ليست المملكة السحرية.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But it is -- oh, I'm sorry, I didn't mean to --
لكنها كذلك -- أوه، أنا آسف، لم أكن أعني أن --
-- sorry.
-- آسف.
We won't talk about Santa Claus then.
إذاً لن نتحدث عن سانتا كلاوس .
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But Disney World is wonderfully true to itself.
لكن عالم ديزني صادقة مع نفسها بصورة مدهشة.
Right? Just wonderfully true to itself.
صحيح؟ صادقة مع نفسها بصورة مدهشة.
When you are there you are just immersed
حينما تكون هناك فأنت مغمور تماماً
in this wonderful environment.
في هذه البيئة الرائعة.
So, it's a fake real.
لذا، فانها زيف حقيقي.
Now the easiest way
الآن أسهل الطرق
to fall down in this,
للوقوع في هذا،
and not be real real,
وليس أن تكون حقيقي حقيقي،
right, the easiest way not to be true to yourself
أسهل الطرق بأن لا تكون صادقاً مع نفسك
is not to understand your heritage,
هو أن لا تفهم تراثك،
and thereby repudiate that heritage.
وعليه تتنصل من ذلك التراث.
Right, the key of being true to yourself is knowing who you are as a business.
حسناً، مفتاح أن تكون صادقاً مع نفسك هو أن تعرف من تكون كعمل تجاري.
Knowing where your heritage is: what you have done in the past.
تعرف أين هو تراثك: ما فعلته في الماضي.
And what you have done in the past limits what you can do,
وما فعلته في الماضي يحد مما يمكنك فعله،
what you can get away with, essentially, in the future.
ما تستطيع الإفلات منه في الأساس، مستقبلياً.
So, you have to understand that past.
لذا، ينبغي أن تفهم ذلك الماضي.
Think about Disney again.
فكروا ب ديزني مجدداً.
Disney,
ديزني،
10 or 15 years ago, right,
قبل 10 أو 15 سنة مضت،
the Disney -- the company that is probably
ديزني-- الشركة التي على الأرجح
best-known for family values out there,
معروفة بقيم الأسرة هناك،
Disney bought the ABC network.
أشترت ديزني شبكة ABC .
The ABC network, affectionately known in the trade
شبكة ABC ، المعروفة بمودة في التجارة
as the T&amp;A network, right --
مثل شبكة T&amp;A، صحيح --
that's not too much jargon, is it?
تلك ليست لهجة كثيرة، أليس كذلك؟
Right, the T&amp;A network. Then it bought Miramax,
حسناً، بعد ذلك أشترت شبكة T&amp;A شركة ميراماكس،
known for its NC-17 fare,
المعروفة بأجرتها NC-17،
and all of a sudden, families everywhere
وفجأة، كل الأسرة في كل مكان
couldn't really trust what they were getting from Disney.
لم تستطع بالفعل الثقة بما يحصلون عليه من ديزني.
It was no longer true to its heritage;
لم تعد صادقة مع تراثها.
no longer true to Walt Disney.
لم تعد صادقة مع والت ديزني.
That's one of the reasons why they're having such trouble today,
تلك أحد أسباب المشاكل التي تواجههم اليوم،
and why Roy Disney is out to get Michael Eisner.
ولماذا يسعى روي ديزني للحصول على مايكل إيسنر.
Because it is no longer true to itself.
لأنها لم تعد صادقة مع نفسها.
So, understand what -- your past limits what you can do in the future.
لذا، أفهم أن ماضيك يحدد لك ما يمكن فعله في المستقبل.
When it comes to being what you say you are, the easiest mistake that companies make
حينما يتعلق الأمر بأن تكون ما تقوله عن نفسه، فأن أسهل الأخطأ التي تفعلها الشركات
is that they advertise
هو أنهم يعلنون
things that they are not.
عن أشياء هي لا تجسدهم.
That's when you're perceived as fake, as a phony company --
وذلك عندما يُنظر لك كزائف، مثل شركة مصطنعة--
advertizing things that you're not.
تعلن عن أشياء لا تجسدها.
Think about any hotel, any airline,
فكروا بالفنادق، أي خطوط طيران،
any hospital.
أي مستشفى.
Right, if you could check into the ads, you'd have a great experience.
إذا لم تستطع التأكد من الإعلانات، فليس لديك تجربة عظيمة.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
But unfortunately, you have to experience the actual hotel,
لكن بكل أسف، ينبغي عليك تجريب الفندق في الواقع،
airline and hospital, and then you have that disconnect.
خط الطيران والمستشفى، ثم تحصل على ذلك الإنقطاع.
Then you have that perception that you are phony.
ثم تحصل على المفهوم بأنك زائف.
So, the number one thing to do when it comes to being what you say you are,
إذاً، فأن أول شئ تفعله حينما يتعلق الأمر بأن تجسد ما تقوله عن نفسك،
is to provide places for people to experience
هو تقديم أماكن للناس لإختبار
who you are.
من أنت.
For people to experience who you are.
للناس لإختبار من أنت.
Right, it's not advertising does it.
صحيح، ليس الإعلان ما يفعل هذا.
That's why you have companies like Starbucks,
لهذا لدينا شركات مثل إستار بوكس،
right, that doesn't advertise at all.
صحيح، ذلك لا يعلن بتاتاً.
They said, you want to know who we are, you have to come experience us.
إنهم يقولون، فأنت تريد معرفة من نحن، ينبغي عليك الحضور لتجريبنا.
And think about the economic value they have provided
وفكروا حول القيمة الإقتصادية التي قدموها
by that experience.
بتلك التجربة.
Right? Coffee, at its core, is what?
صحيح؟ القهوة، وجوهرها، هي ماذا؟
Right? It's beans; right? It's coffee beans.
صحيح؟ إنها البن، صحيح؟ إنها حبة البن.
You know how much coffee is worth, when treated as a commodity as a bean?
هل تعلمون كم تساوي القهوة، حينما يتم التعامل معها كسلعة مثل حبوب البن؟
Two or three cents per cup -- that's what coffee is worth.
سنتان أو ثلاثة للكوب-- ذلك ما تستحقه القهوة.
But grind it, roast it, package it, put it on a grocery store shelf,
لكن أطحنها، أقليها، عبئها، وضعها على رف متجر البقالة،
and now it'll cost five, 10, 15 cents,
والآن تكلف خمسة، عشرة، 15 سنتاً،
when you treat it as a good.
حينما تتعامل معها كبضاعة.
Take that same good,
خذ نفس السلعة تلك
and perform the service of actually brewing it for a customer,
وقم بالخدمة التي تختمرها للزبون،
in a corner diner, in a bodega, a kiosk somewhere,
في زاوية العشاء، في بودغا، كشك في مكان ما،
you get 50 cents, maybe a buck
تحصل على 50 سنتاً، ربما دولار
per cup of coffee.
لكل كوب من القهوة.
But surround the brewing of that coffee
لكن يحيط بإختمار تلك القهوة
with the ambiance of a Starbucks,
مع أجواء إستار بوكس،
with the authentic cedar that goes inside of there,
مع الأرز الحقيقي الذي يدخل هناك،
and now, because of that authentic experience,
والآن، بسبب تلك التجربة الأصلية،
you can charge two, three, four, five dollars
يمكنك أن تدفع أثنين، ثلاثة، أربعة، خمسة دولارات
for a cup of coffee.
مقابل كوب القهوة.
So, authenticity is becoming
إذا، تصبح الأصالة
the new consumer sensibility.
هي حساسية المستهلك الجديد.
Let me summarize it, for the business people in the audience,
لنقوم بتلخيصها، لرجال الأعمال ضمن هذا الحضور،
with three rules, three basic rules.
مع ثلاث قواعد، ثلاث قواعد أساسية.
One, don't say you're authentic
واحد، لا تقول أنك أصلي
unless you really are authentic.
إلا إذا كنت حقيقةً أصلي.
Two, it's easier to be authentic
أثنين، من الأسهل أن تكون أصلي
if you don't say you're authentic.
إذا لم تقل أنك أصلي.
And three, if you say you're authentic,
ثلاثة، إذا قلت أنك أصلي،
you better be authentic.
من أفضل أن تكون أصلياً.
And then for the consumers, for everyone else in the audience,
ثم إلى المستهلكين، لكل شخص آخر ضمن الحضور،
let me simply summarize it by saying, increasingly,
دعوني ألخّصها بكل يسر بالقول، بإضطراد،
what we -- what will make us happy,
ما الذي سيجعلنا سعداء،
is spending our time and our money
هو قضاء أوقاتنا وأموالنا
satisfying the desire for authenticity.
بتحقيق رغبة الأصالة.
Thank you.
شكراً لكم.